Hey, Fernund, my eyes are up here.
I'm looking at your spear.
It's magnificent.
But, how does it work?
You stick the pointy end into the machine.
Yes, but, how does it turn foe into friend?
It's simple, really.
Yes?
You wouldn't understand.
What's your proposal?
During the reign of that idiot Carja king,
outlanders often hid items of value from raiders.
Well, I found one.
What is it?
A relic from the Old Ones.
You probably would understand it better than I do.
Unfortunately, it's too high for me to reach.
Uh-huh, and you want me to get it for you?
What a brilliant plan!
You're a much better climber than I am, to be sure.
Get it, bring it back, and we'll split the proceeds.
You're going down!
They're scanning for me.
I dropped it!
It's looking good.
Ready or not…
I'll tuck that away.
It'd be fascinating, if they weren't looking for me.
I'm ready, gotta be.
Just stay out of their way for now.
There!
Low and quiet does it.
Lucky me.
Dusk Mesa.
Now I need to find someplace too high to reach.
If I'm to believe anything Fernund said.
I'll find a use for you.
Well, what do you know?
Aaaand it's empty.
[in the distance]
Spear girl!
Of course.
You found it.
The perfect location for an ambush.
Now throw down that magnificent spear and we'll let you live.
You've obviously heard of me.
You know what I'm capable of.
Why do you think this will turn out well for you?
I like the odds.
Get her!
Why do I bother?
You can see them, they can't see you.
[Outlander mercenary]
She's up on high!
[Carja outlander]
In the name of the Sun, fight back!
That's the last of them.
But Fernund ran off.
Back to the Meridian docks, I'll bet.
I'd have to leave something else behind.
Keep that for later.
[Carja guard]
Don't ask me where to go if you're lost.
I'm a guard, not the Town Crier.
[Carja guard]
Machines or bandits try to get past me, they'll have a fight.
Mark my words.
Your aid to the Carja Sundom
in these times of strife is appreciated.
That's the official response.
I'd say I can tell you've done the work by the look on your face.
Two of them got themselves killed.
The other welcomed a fight to the end.
They would have found death with or without you,
taken others with them.
That's what I told myself.
Smart girl. Doubt we'll meet again, so go in light.
[Prisoner]
There's nothing so strange about old men dying…
[Carja guard]
Don't look to me, I'm just a guard.
I don't get involved in politics.
[Carja guard]
Had to take over my brother's shift today.
It's the Sun's rise and he's off in the court playing nobleman.
[Carja guard]
There are no shadows under the noonday sun. Words to live by.
Apocashitstorm Tour, day seven.
I was three months out of rehab
when we went camping out here.
Wyatt went to sleep early.
So it was just the two of us.
When we stayed up and watched the Perseids.
After, as we talked about the stars and space tech,
I suddenly knew what I wanted to do with my life.
Shadows are getting long.
Low and quiet does it.
Passed the test.
Quietly…
[Cultist]
…here, doesn't look good.
Eclipse. What are they doing here?
They're still looking.
[Cultist]
There's something in that grass over there.
Should've brought a cart.